更多精彩请关注 极地影视 www.jddy.net
如果血液不沸腾, 血管里流的就是水
If yet your blood does not rage, then it is waterthat flows in your veins.
青春美好有何用, 如果不奉献给祖国
For what is the flush of youth, if it is not of service to the motherland.
[英属印度, 二十世纪初]
British Indian, early twentieth century
稍等McKinley先生, 一个革命者遇见了另一个革命者
Just a minute Mr. McKinley, one revolutionary is meeting another.
谢谢. 走吧?
Thank you. Shall we go?
抱歉必须这样结束
I'm sorry it had to end this way.
这不是结束McKinley先生, 而是开始
This isn't the end Mr. McKinley. This is just the beginning.
我们死后还会有更多, 更多
There will be others after we have gone. Many others.
我一直认为世界上有两种人
I always believe there are 2 kinds of people in this world
面对死亡哭喊的人
Men that go to death screaming
面对死亡安静的人
Men who go to that death in silence
然后我遇到了第三种
Then I met a third kind
有时在梦里, 我仍见到他们最后一次走过
Sometimes in my dreams I can still see them making that long last walk
他们没有畏缩
They never folded
没有尝试挣扎
they never
尤其记得的
but above all of else
是他们的眼睛
I remember his eyes
看着我的神情
How they looked at me
清澈, 坚定, 毫不退缩
clear, defined, never wavering
时间到
It's time
片名: 芭萨堤的颜色 /Basanti: 春季, 又意金黄, 印度的爱国色彩/
Rang De Basanti
我在德里的联系人Sonia正在寻找演员
So Sonia, my contact in delhi she's found some..
但是目前担心的是经费
We are gonna have to worry with some money to securite it
那边什么都是现金
Everything's cash out there
我走错房间了吗?
Have I come to the wrong meeting?
我们收到上面的指示: 缩减经费
We've had a directive from above- budget cot
所以我们必须做出艰难的决定
So we've had to take some very tough decisions
抱歉, Sue
sorry, Sue
真的很抱歉
really sorry
如果要做, 甘地是没问题 - 甘地有卖头
If you do the episode, then Ghadi, that'll work for us - Ghandi sells
可以是.. 甚至罗宾汉, 可..
I suggest.., even Robin Hood, but..
这个革命, Bhagat Singh
This revolution, is this, Bhagat Singh
Chandrashekhar Ali..
Chandrashekhar Ali?
Azad, OK?
Chandrashekhar Azad azad, OK?
而且Azad意思是自由
and azad means freedom
Azad, 对不起. 我知道它的意思, Sue
azad sorry, I know what it means, Sue
我不相信
I don't belive this
什么都准备好了, 这个花了两年 我甚至还去上了夜校印度课程
You know everything is set up, I've been working on this for 2 years. I've been going to bloody indian night classes
瞧, 拜托..
look, please
这个故事值得讲述
this story deserves to be told
这是我爷爷的日记, 他亲眼见证
This is my grandfather's diary, he was an eye witness
写满了真实的对话, 每个字都有
it's filled with real conversations, they have very words
勇士们, 23岁正好抗击帝国
boys, no older than 23 fighting the empire
这是个重要的故事, 非常重要的..
that's an important story, a bloody important..
这不是结束McKinley先生
This is not the end, Mr. McKinley,
能和你谈谈吗?
Can I talk to you?
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
去印度, 去拍纪录片
To India, to shoot a documentary
我会给你寄明信片
I'll send you a postcard
怎么寄? 用什么寄?
How? with what?
操你
Shove it.
让开!
Get out of the way! Scoot!
夫人别紧张, 第一次来印度?
You come India first time madam? Yes!
结婚了吗? 我和我的妻子也结婚了
Are you married? Even me and my wife get married
不好意思, 是我来接她的
Excuse me, she's with me
见到你真好 - 不敢相信你来了, 终于见到你了
Good to see you - I can't believe you are here. It's happening at last
对不起没有早点通知你
Sorry about the short notice.
天! 你的印地语说得真好
Gosh! Your Hindi has really improved.
没有什么可担心的
Hey Sue, no need to worry...
什么都齐了, 到处都做了宣传
...everything has been taken care of posters have been put up everywhere.
还在广播里说了
It's also been announced on radio.
看吧, 人会排着对来试镜的
...just see, they'll be lining up forthe auditions.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我没跟你说, 其实我是一个人来的
I didn't tell you. The truth is that I've come alone.
没有钱, 也没有制片人来
...no money, no producer is going to arrive.
我知道
I know
你知道?
You knew it!
有个叫Beth Williams的, 来了电话..
After Alice, there was a call from a certain Beth Williams...
她通知我计划取消, 你也辞职了
...she informed me of the cancellation of the show and also my services.
顺便问下, 你是不是用印地语骂她了?
...did you abuse her in Hindi?
她想知道什么意思, 我跟她说了, 仔细地解释了一遍
She wanted to know what it meant. I explained to her in graphic detail.
你真是不可思议, Sonia
You are amazing... Sonia.
这是德里大学
This is Delhi University
我来帮你拿行李
Let me help you with your luggage.
多少钱?                          夫人已经说了
How much? - Ma'am I've already told you.
Ravi, 请把行李搬到我的房间
Ravi, please get all the luggage to our room.
哪个国家, 女士?
Which country, madam?
印度, 我希望
India, I hope
休息一下, 我明天再来
Get some rest now. I'll see you tomorrow...
要有什么需要, 打我的电话
...lf you need anything you have my number.
我们走吧, Ravi
Let's go Ravi.
我爷爷说得没错
My grandfarther is right
他说你要是来印度, 会一见钟情
He said when you come to India, it's love of a first sight
我是Dabul
Hi, it's double speaking
我的爱好是摩托, 美人, 和健美
My hobbies are, bikes, babes, and body building
我不行
I can't do this.
试一下
Just try once
我不行
I can't do this.
我应该出演, 因为我跟Priety Zinta一样有酒窝
I deserve a role because I have dimples just like Priety Zinta.
不要唱, 就复述"Vande Matram"
- Vande Matram? Don't sing. Just recite "Vande Matram". - Vande Matram?
举起手来说: Vande Matram
Raise your hand and say VANDE MATRAM! VANDE Matram!
说大声点, Vande Matram!
Speak loudly, VANDE MATRAM! Vande MATRAM.
响亮地说: Vande Matram
Loudly and proudly, VANDE MATRAM! Vande MATRAM
我把生命献给了祖国的自由
I have dedicated my life to the freedom of this nation.
我知道你希望我结婚
I know you want me to get married.
但自由就是我的新娘
...but FREEDOM is my bride.
我知道.. 我知道.. 嗯..
I know... I know... that...
我知道.. 你希望我结婚
I know... that you want me to get married...
但自由就是我的新娘
...but my bride is FREEDOM
你顺从的儿子, Bhagat Singh
Your obedient son, BHAGAT SINGH.
Bhagat Singh
BHAGAT SINGH.
Bhagat Singh.
Bhagat Singh
我的名字叫Bhagat Singh
My name is Bhagat Singh.
茶?
Tea!
谢谢
Thanks.
有些失望, 对吗?
Depressed huh?
有一两个还是可以出演
One or two of them can be used for minor roles...
但Azad, Bhagat Singh, 没有接近的
...but no one's even close for Azad or Bhagat Singh.
我想, 这都怪我
I guess it's all my fault.
不Sonia, 你是我的坚强后盾
No Sonia. You're my rock.
是我的错
It's my fault
我不该来
I should never have come
瞧Sue, 不要这么灰心
Sue, don't get so dejected.
我看我们得放松下
I think we need a break
走, 我们去玩下.                    我没有心情
Let's go and have some fun. I'm in no mood Sonia.
来吧, 我们去教室
Come on, we are going to the classroom
来啊
Come on
Aslam... Sue McKinley
Aslam... Sue McKinley.
你也在大学里学习吗?
You too study at the University?
哇, 她的印地语真好
Wow! Her Hindi is great.
我们在那住, 在那吃 可还没人咒过我们在那学习
We live there, eat there but no one has ever accused us of studying there.
那些疯子干吗?
What are those maniacs upto?
那是DJ
That's DJ...
DJ我爱你!
DJ I love you!!!
还有Sukhi
That's Sukhi.
DJ我爱你!
DJ I love you!!!
我也爱你宝贝!
I love you too baby!
他妈的表现狂
Damn exhibitionists.
那白痴就是改不了
The idiots will never change.
来吧伙计, 我们喝翻天!
Come on dude, let's rock it!
加油, Sukhi, 我爱你!
Sukhi I love you!
他没事吗?
Is he OK?
Sukhi就喜欢这样
That's his natural state.
怎么样Sukhi, 身子还好使吧?
Sukhi, all parts working?
我的妈! Sonia旁边的是谁?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Sue, 这是DJ. DJ这是Sue
Sue this is DJ. DJ this is Sue.
Sue? 她这么红润该叫Gulabo(玫瑰)才对
Sue? She's so pink her name should be Gulabo (Rose).
真是个"辣妹"
She's quite hot...
我是说, 真冷啊.. (用英语说, 以为Sue不懂印地语)
Perfect for this cold.
Karan, 你救了我的命, I love you
Karan you saved my life. I love you!
Aslam..
Aslam...
你也救了我
...you too saved my life,
I love you too
I love you too!
好吧..
It's ok.
她肯定也救了我的命..
She must have saved my life too...
不, Sukhi! 她没救你的命
No! Sukhi! She didn't save your life.
没关系, 有一天她会救我的
No problem. One day she'll save my life.
放松点伙计, 是你嫂子呢
Relax Dude! She is your sister-in-law.
失去控制
LOOSE CONTROL
我是叛逆
I'm a REBEL.
这里没有学生, 没有老师管教
There's aren't any students here, no teachers to suffer.
这是没有教条的学校 聪明的家伙, 好好去想吧
It's a school without rules out here Hey Genius, go figure.
你就这样傻坐着?
Sukhi you just sit and watch like a dumb-ass...
DJ可一秒也不放过
DJ doesn't waste a second.
他是个人物
He's a stud.
大家怎么样?             嗨Rahul, 还好吧
Hi! How's everybody? Hi Rahul! What's up?
一大堆工作
Got a few gigs lined up.
广播电台搞得怎样了?
How's your radio thing going?
顺利么?
Did anything work out?
"全印"电台给了我晚间档
All India Radio has given me a night slot.
不错啊
Cool...
不完全是. 人们都睡觉了, 我就在播音
Not really. When the whole world's sleeping I'm on air.
有人也经常熬夜
But people stay up late...
罪犯, 失眠患者, 保安, 还有白痴!
Criminals, insomniacs, watchmen and idiots!
你们就拿我的损失开玩笑吧
Have your fun at my expense.
说到损失, 我能不能..
Speaking of expenses... Can I...
谢谢伙计
Thanks, Man
先走了. 有烟没?
See you guys. Got a cigarette?
难以置信
Fabulous!
是我爸的钱, 他有的是钱
It's my Dad's money. He's got lots of it...
不许放污秽的西方音乐
Stop this Western music, this obscenity!
还要说多少遍?
How many times do I have to make you understand this!
把国家的文化都污染了
Polluting the culture of this country...
现在马上走人, 滚!
Leave this place right now. LEAVE!
你怎么就不明白, 笨蛋!
Can't you understand, idiot!
这是最后一次警告!
This is your last warning...
从现在起, 这里再没有西方音乐
...from now on, nobody plays any Western music out here.
没有下流舞蹈
No lewd dancing!
不然就打断你们的腿!
Or I'll break your legs.
凭什么来警告我们? 你不喜欢就别来
Who are you to warn us? If you don't like it, don't come here.
你他妈的巴基斯坦人
You bloody Pakistani!
我们来做个了断
Let's finish it.
最后的警告, 听明白了?
Last warning! Got it?
印度万岁!
Long live India!
你们敢动Aslam, 让你们好看..
You touch Aslam and see what I do to you...
让你妈都认不出来你
...even your mother won't recognize you.
见过猴子屁股没? 收拾完你让你一样红
Ever seen a baboons arse? Yours will be as red after I've finished with you.
长官, 我们会解决的
Sir, I'm sure we can work it out.
拿着..
Keep this...
那是贿赂吗?
Is that a bribe?
欢迎来印度, Sue
Welcome to India, Sue
有人饿了没? 我都饥肠辘辘了
Anyone hungry? I'm famished.
Sue, 想坐车吗?
Hey Sue, Want a ride?
你有保险没?
You got a insurance, no?
怎么样?
How're you?
宝贝! 快过来..
Hey honey! Come here you...
你要出了什么事, 我饶不了你
If something happened to you, I'd have killed you.
你就这样迎接你男朋友?
Is this any way to greet your boyfriend?
还好吗?
How're you?
空军上校Ajay Rathore
Fligh Lt. Ajay Rathore
就是我
Don't miss that
快点, 我都要饿死了
Hurry guys, I'm famished.
这没有你们吃的
You won't get any food here.
亲爱的老妈, 我饿了                    什么"老妈"
Dear Ma, I'm hungry - You do not get anything
走开, 这也没你吃的
Stay away!
我在肚子里怀了你九个月
...I carried you in my stomach for nine months...
又给你换洗了几年的尿布
...and washed your bum for years.
滚开!
Get lost!
也没人想着来问问Mitro是死是活?
Does anyone bother to check if Mitro is alive or dead?
怎么了?
What's up?
你又喝醉!
You're drunk again.
不不..
No. No. No.
妈先去拿点吃的, 整晚说我们都行
First give us food ma, and then yell at us all night.
你们都没吃饭吗?
None of you have eaten?
Sonia你变得更瘦了
Sonia you've lost even more weight.
真的? Mitro
Really... Mitro
现在的女孩子都是骨头, 肉倒少了
The girls of today have more bones and less flesh...
还怎么生孩子啊?
How will you bear children?
Aslam, 你还好吗孩子?
Aslam, how are you my son?
他才是我真正的儿子, 问问我情况
He is my true son who bothers to check on me.
而你这小子..
And you...
走了这么久也没消息                    哪有啊
don't give a care
看啊妈, 我给你带谁来了
Look ma, what I brought for you.
你的媳妇, 她的名字叫Sue
Your daughter-in-law. Her name is Sue.
一个外国人?
What? Aforeigner?
专程把她从伦敦带过来, 所以离开了这么久
Brought her especially from London. That's why I was away for so long.
我告诉她你从伦敦来
I am telling her London first of yours
请祝福我, 妈
Give me your blessings Ma.
您儿子真调皮
Your son's such a brat.
我的老天!
God!
她懂印地语?
She understands Hindi!
你真的都听得懂?
You really understand everything? Yes.
我要去睡觉了, 你们的床铺都准备好了 不要熬到太晚
I'm going off to sleep. Your beds are all ready. No need to drive so late at night.
我看到了那些人, 仿佛从爷爷的故事中跳了出来
I saw the man, like they leaped out of grandpa's story
Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad,  Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru 还有Durga Bhabhi
Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad, Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru and Durga Bhabhi
他们就坐在我前面
They were sitting right there in front of me
在想什么呢?
Sue, where are you?
你们能在我电影里演出吗?
Will you guys act in my film?
什么?
What?
在我的电影里演出, 你们再合适不过
You guys acting in my film, you guys are perfect
你们笑什么? 我是她电影里的男主角
Hey, why are you guys laughing? I'm the hero of her film.
演戏我们是好手
Yeah we guys are champions when it comes to acting...
整天他们就会搞怪
...clowning around is all they do.
我是认真的
I'm serious, OK?
你们演Bhagat Singh, Chandrashekhar Azad, Ashfaqulla Khan, Rajguru非常合适
The four of you will be perfect for the roles...
而Sonia就做我的Durga Bhabhi
And Sonia will be my Durga Bhabhi.
她真的懂印地语
She really knows Hindi!
说这些爱国主义很无聊
All this talk of patriotism is boring.
无聊? 他们为了你们国家的自由献出了生命
Boring? These guys gave their lives for the freedom of your country.
什么自由? 你见过这国家的状况吗?
What freedom? Have you seen the state of this country?
等下, Karan. 我国家有信心
Excuse me! I believe in this country, Karan.
要不然, 我努力都是为了什么?
Otherwise, why would I be fighting for it?
也许是因为很酷.. 开着昂贵的飞机
Maybe because it's cool! Being a pilot... flying an expensive plane.
穿着帅气夹克
You get to wear sexy jackets...
还有女孩子.. 女孩子喜欢制服男人
And the women... women love men in uniforms.
当然我喜欢做飞机员, 很酷
Sure I love being a pilot. Sure it's cool.
但我也为祖国自豪, 能为她献出生命
But I also feel proud of my country, and I can give my life for it.
有什么自豪?
Proud of what?
人口激增?
...this country's exploding population?
或高失业率?                          还是腐败?
...or unemployment... or corruption?
哪一样让你感到自豪?
Which of these are you really proud of?
得了伙计, 没有完美, 只有让它变得更好
No country's perfect Karan. We've got to make it better.
对
Right.
好, Ajay, 你让国家变得更好
Ok, Ajay you make this country perfect.
我一拿到学位就去美国, 离开这个垃圾场
The minute I get my degree I'm out of this dump...
你没这个能耐
You won't be able to leave us and go.
等着瞧
Wait and see
她印地语真的不错!
She speaks Hindi so well!
你们怎么不早说, 害我出丑
Why didn't you tell me you idiot. I was making a fool of myself.
起码跟他们说说, 求你
At least ask them once.
看来你是不放弃
So you won't give up.
OK, 不过他们不会去的
Ok. But nobody will turn up.
我会, 我跟他们说, DJ答应你
I'll get them. That's a promise.
Karan, 把烟熄掉
Karan put your cigarette out.
爷爷
Grandpa!
老天保佑, 什么时候来的?
God bless you. When did you come?
昨晚上
Just last night.
是谁?
Who?
DJ的爷爷
DJ's grandpa
早啊Karan
Good morning Karan.
这么早就回来了?
Back so early?
我不知道你在家
I didn't know you were in town.
一小时前刚到
Just arrived an hour ago.
飞了很久
It was a long flight...
大学里还好吧?
Everything Ok at college?
都好, 爸
Everything's fine Dad.
等下, 想好明年去哪所美国大学没?
Have you decided which American university you want to go to next year?
密歇根, 卡内基, 梅隆, 沃顿..
Michigan, Carnegie, Mellon, Wharton...
我知道有哪些
I know the list.
等等
Karan wait!
我听不清楚, 等下打过来
I can't hear you clearly call me later.
我知道你也清楚有哪些大学
I know that you know about the lists.
但生活不会自己创造
But life doesn't just happen to you.
需要你来规划
You've got to plan it...
这个国家每秒都有人出生
Every second someone is born in this country.
没人关心他们, 政府没有老天也没有
Nobody cares about them. Neitherthe government nor God.
不用
No
做点什么, 不然会成为他们一员
Do something. Or else you will be one of them.
拜托不要跟我说教了
Please, don't start with your lectures.
简化主义
SMS generation
超过四句话都成了"说教"
Any conversation that goes beyond four lines becomes a lecture.
这信号不好. 稍等, 走开下Karan
Signal's weak here. Give me a second. Excuse me Karan.
好了说吧
Now shoot
那就把交易取消
The deal is off then
我们不感兴趣..
we are not interested...
俄国货本来质量就难说, 凭什么自大?
You know Russian quality is doubtful, they can't afford to be arrogant.
反正我们的出价, 比市场上高很多
Anyway in the open market they'd not get anything close to the price we're offering.
你也知道在印度, 每次交易都没人负责
And you know how many fathers there are to every deal in India. Nothing.
跟他们说我们不谈价, 他们该把钱汇给我们
Tell them we won't bargain, they should wire the money to us.
我就说的, 他们不会来的
I did try to warn you... they won't turn up.
不, DJ答应过我
DJ promised me.
哦! DJ答应过你
Oh! DJ promised you!
你们真的是拍电影的
So you really are a filmmaker?
Karan.. 怎么这么晚?
Karan... Why are you so late?
其他人呢?
And where are the others?
印度年轻枪手
The Young Guns Of India
令人印象深刻
Very dramatic.
你要去哪?
Where are you going?
走, 这也是选角的一部分
Well that's one part cast.
我肯定Karan会告诉我们他的朋友们在哪
I am sure Karan can tell us where his friends are.
八分
She's an eight. Yeah!
哇, 九分
Wow! Nine.
多好的女孩! Oye Chotu...
What a girl! Oye Chotu...
给我杯茶
...get me a cup of tea...
二分, 让她走人
Two, looks like she's got the flu...
六..
Six...
十!                             什么?
Ten! What?
伙计.. 看那双腿!
Dude... Iooks at those legs!
摆起来宝贝, 左右..
Shake it baby, shake it...
哦糟糕!
Oh shit!
别傻了, 起码也有八分
Don't be silly, that's at least an eight.
就知道你们在这贪吃
Thought I'd find you stuffing your faces.
这帮懒鬼, 干不出什么好事
You lazy good-for-nothings.
我们正想去的..
We were about to come... but...
其实是在等Karan
...we are waiting for Karan actually.
是吗? Karan?
Oh! So you were waiting for Karan. Yeah!
Karan准时去了
Karan was there on time.
我们在这等, 他却在那等
We are waiting for him here and he was waiting for us there.
把我们搞得晕头转向
What confusion...
你是Ashfaqulla Khan
You're Ashfaqulla Khan.
你是Rajguru                              主角对吗?
You're Rajguru. The hero right!
你, 知道是谁吗?
And you know who you are?
伪装骗术大师
The Master of Disguise and Deception.
Chandrashekhar Azad
Chandrashekhar Azad.
嘴唇真性感..
What lips...
好好看台词, 我们明天见
Learn the lines properly, we meet tomorrow.
八点准时排演!
8 a.m. Sharp!
九..
Nine
八点整!                        哦八点
Sharp at eight.
我们已经浪费一天了
We've already wasted a day...
Aslam, 你嫂子生气时更好看了
Aslam, your sister-in-law looks even better when she's angry.
在干什么呢, Laxman?
What are you doing Laxman?
党高层对你的工作很满意
Party High Command is really happy with your work.
你抵触西方文化做的努力
These demonstrations that you have started against Western culture...
令其它党派相形见绌
...they've helped us overshadow other parties.
这是给你和你的朋友的
This is for you. And this is for your boys.
没有必要, Mishraji
It's not necessary, Mishraji.
我是为了党不是为了钱
I'm not doing this for money.
我真的相信我党的理念
I really believe in the principles of my party.
很好Laxman..
That's fine Laxman...
但每次行动也需要燃油.. 拿着
...but every movement needs fuel... Keep it.
3月14日
March the 14th
我们开始了排演
We started the rehearsals
说我是紧张远远不够
To say I was nervous would be an understatement
没有什么能把我打倒
There is nothing you can do to break me.
因为疼痛是我的朋友
"Because I have made pain my friend."
因为我紧握死亡的手指
"...As I hold Death's fingers."
DJ傻瓜, 不要影响我集中注意力
DJ idiot, don't spoil my concentration.
大家认真点
Please guy, be serious
看啊, 死亡的手指..
Look, Death's finger.
我已把自己献给了国家的自由
"I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
我知道你希望我成家, 但自由就是我的新娘
...I know you want me to get married, but I have made freedom my bride..."
你顺从的儿子, Bhagat Singh
"Your obedient son, Bhagat Singh."
谁会这么说? 你顺从的儿子
Who talks like this for God's sake?
自由是我新娘, 他有什么问题?
My bride is freedom...
我看这句台词对Sukhi挺合适
I think it's a good line for Sukhi...
反正也没有女孩子会嫁给他
Since no girl is ever going to marry him...
就让自由作他的新娘吧
Let freedom be his bride.
笑吧混蛋, 笑吧
Laugh bastards, laugh.
看啊, 是"自由小姐"竞选穿的纱丽
This is the sari round of the Miss Freedom contest.
这样能让我感受角色
Just thought it would help me get into the character.
这样是不行的
Look guys this isn't going to work.
你们要认真地感受角色
You have to work hard to bring out the characters.
只有用心表演..
Unless you emote from within...
你们才会理解这些角色
...you won't understand these characters.
试一下.. 会从你们内心流露出来
Try... it will come from within you.
他已经抓住他的角色了
See, he's got a hold of his character already.
你理解人物挺快的
You understood the character pretty fast.
不要胡闹了
Would you stop it?
住口一边去
Just shut up and get out
看哪! 你看起来也完全是个革命者
See! Now you look like a revolutionary!
Gulabo不管怎么说, 你还需要我来创造情绪
Whatever you say Gulabo, you need me to create the mood.
DJ你看看
DJ watch it.
现在她沮丧了
Now she's upset!
Bhagat Singh才23岁, 这是他说的话
Those are the words of a 23 year old.
这也是他牺牲的年龄
That's how old Bhagat Singh was when he died: 23.
那个时代不同
Those were different times Sue.
现在, 你要是跟人说, 把生命献给祖国
Today, if you tell people that you want to give your life for your country...
他们会说你傻
...they'll call you nuts.
正是
Exactly.
我觉得和我没什么共同点
I don't think I can relate to this...
行了, 不要想了
That's it. Don't think.
去感觉, 读这些文字, 去感觉
Feel. Just read the words, Feel them.
何不再来一次?
Why don't we try again?
再试一次
Let's try again...
我已把自己献给了国家的自由
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
工作, 安定的生活, 都已经不再重要
...a job... a well settled life... these things don't matter anymore.
我知道你希望我成家, 但是自由就是我的新娘
...I know you want me to get married, but I have made freedom my bride...
我, 印度母亲的儿子, 在此庄严发誓..
I swear on Mother India...
Aslam是个人物..
This Aslam is a real stud...
看看他的本事, 作诗, 相手..
Take a look at the packaging. Poetry, palmistry!
DJ, 我有时怕会单身一辈子
DJ, I'm scared at times that I'll remain a bachelor all my life.
相信我, 我不会让你到死也是条单身汉
Trust me I won't let you die a bachelor.
保证?
Promise?
这是DJ的保证
It's DJ's promise.
你会书写人们的命运..
You'll be writing people's destinies...
你的爱情线很强
Your love line is very strong...
你命中的男人会穿着黑T恤到来, 并说:
The man of your dreams will come along in a black T-shirt and say:
我到底有没有爱情线?
Do I even have a love line?
你一定在厕所里洗掉了
You must have washed it off in the loo.
'国防部长Shastri也牵涉到MIG-21佣金丑闻'
"Defence Minister Shastri has also been implicated in the MIG-21 kickbacks scandal,"
真教人郁闷
This is really depressing.
'这是无耻的谎言, 我要求对此调查"
"This is a blatant lie. I am ordering an investigation."
再见伙计
See you guys.
你是我伙计, 我送你回家
You're my buddy... I'll drop you home.
我不需要帮助, 才两条街
I don't need any help, it's just two lanes away.
我们没醉到, 连你家都不记得在哪
We aren't so drunk... that we've forgotten where you live.
一帮傻瓜
Idiots!
你有这样的朋友很幸运
You're very lucky to have friends like them.
有一天都会结束的
One day this will all end.
我们会走上不同的路
We'll all go our separate ways.
但是你们可以保持联系
But you can always keep in touch.
不会的
Doesn't happen.
生活会变得繁忙
Life gets busy.
各种问题, 找工作, 房子, 赚钱
Too many problems. Getting a job, a house, money.
在学校我们是命运的主人
In college we are the masters of our destinies...
毕业后我们是命运的奴仆
But after college we have to dance to fate's tune.
知道吗Gulabo, 我5年前就毕业了
You know Gulabo. I passed out 5 years ago...
但我还在混..
...but I still hang around...
我不明白
I don't understand.
我一直不想离开学校
...I don't ever want to leave college.
为什么?
Why?
起码在学校人们认识我
At least in the campus I'm someone... people know me.
DJ是个人物..
DJ's somebody...
人们对我抱有期望
People expect me to do something big in life.
但是等我出来了
But when I'm out on the streets...
我不过就像国家的那些懒汉
I'll just be like the rest of the slobs in this country.
什么也不是, 又怕
Nameless. Faceless. Scared. Just walking the streets...
喝了点酒, 把什么都说了
It's the beer... Everything came out.
你知道我还怕什么?
You know what else I'm scared of?
在你的电影里表演
Acting in your film.
别担心, 有可靠的人保护
Don't worry... you're in safe hands.
去哪了?
Where have you been?
你好大伯
Hello Uncle... How are you?
我们明天见Aslam
We'll catch up tomorrow Aslam...
你喝酒了?
You've been drinking?
爸, 你知道我不喝酒
Dad, you know I don't drink.
他们一无是处                     不管怎样他们是我朋友
Good-for-nothings... Whatever, they're my friends.
什么朋友! 他们不感到害臊..
Friends! They feel no shame standing in front of...
满口酒气站在你爸面前
...yourfather with alcohol on their breath.
你怎么不在我们的圈子里找朋友?
Why can't you get friends in your own community?
为什么跟这些让你败坏, 污辱信仰的人?
Why do you make friends with people who corrupt you, disgrace your religion...
这跟信仰无关, 爸
This has nothing to do with religion, Father.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
跟你父亲说话小心点
Don't raise your voice in the presence of yourfather.
他说得对
He's right.
这个国家从不接受穆斯林, 也绝不会
This country has never accepted Muslims and it never will...
你怎能这么漠视?
How can you be so passive!
你看见我跟印度教人混一起过吗?
Do you ever see me mixing with a Hindu?
我不是你, 你也不像你一样
I'm not you and I don't want to be like you brother.
我不能让自己满是仇恨
I can't fill myself with so much hate...
胆小鬼你这点是改不了的
Coward that's what you are.
不要说了
Stop it!
我在这里受够了, 每天都是同样的争吵
I feel suffocated in this house. It's the same old thing every single day...
我们的墓地每年都会有狂欢
Carnivals will be held on our graves every year,
我们为国家死后, 留下的就是这个
That's all that will be left of us, when we die for our country.
说得好Ashfaq Sahab..
Well said Ashfaq Sahab...
英国人要是听见, 马上会离开
If the English could hear you they would leave this country in a moment.
有什么决定?
So what has been decided?
有一辆火车经过Kakori, 我们在那偷帝国的钱
We'll steal the Empire's money from the train that passes Kakori.
我们用那些钱来买武器
And with that money we will buy arms.
Bismil会仔细解释
Bismil will explain everything.
是Bismil.. 我的Ram在哪?
Yes Bismil... Where is my Ram?
我还是找不到我的Ramprasad Bismil
I just can't find my Ramprasad Bismil.
放松, 会找到的
Relax. We will find him.
在哪? 怎么找?
But where? How?
很快, 你不是..
Very soon. Don't you wo...
你们在这是不会找到Ramprasad Bismil的
You won't get Ramprasad Bismil out here.
你们需要一个真正的印度人
You need a true Indian.
你在一群想成为西方人的人里..
How can you find Indian revolutionaries amongst...
怎么找得到印度的革命家?
...people who want to be Westerners?
别听他说, 我们走
Ignore him. Let's go.
Ramprasad Bismil希望重生100次..
Ramprasad Bismil wished to be reborn a hundred times...
以此为他的祖国献身100次
...so that he could give his life for his country a hundred times over.
我们走Sue
Let's go Sue.
那在哪才能找到我的Bismil?
So where do you think I can find my Bismil?
真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
这一天我们与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白的脸庞
This day, we walk along with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
我们不惧怕残忍尖刀, 我们的勇气更为锋利
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
不要错把沉默当成屈服, 后面是那滚滚熔岩
Mistake not our silence for submission. For beneath lies lava, molten.
哦烈士, 哦英勇的人 有一天敌人也会赞颂你
O Martyre, O men of valour. One day the enemy will sing your praises.
当真理来临, 我们会显示勇气
We will show our mettle when the moment of truth arrives...
因为勇气是行动, 而不是夸夸其谈
...for courage lives in deeds, not boastful lies.
我们聚集在敌人的巢穴, 朋友们..
We've gathered in the enemy's lair, my friend...
渴望为了祖国献出生命
In the hope of dying for our motherland.
我们不惧怕残忍尖刀, 我们的勇气更为锋利
We will not fearthose cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
这一天我们与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白的脸庞
This day, we walk along with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
我们不惧怕残忍尖刀, 我们的勇气更为锋利
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
Sue, 这里不是伦敦
Sue, this isn't London
你不知道像Laxman Pandey这样的人渣
You don't know what kind of scum, men like Laxman Pandey are.
瞧Sue, 他要是也参与进来, 那我不能来演
Look Sue if he is a part of this, then I can't do the film.
你要是有问题, 当着我的面说
If you have any problems with me say it on my face.
不要像个懦夫在背后说坏话
Don't stab me in the back like a coward.
Pandey你走开, 我们不想惹麻烦
Pandey leave! We don't want trouble...
说你呢懦夫, 你刚才说什么?
Speak you coward. What were you saying?
Aslam, 你去哪?
Aslam, where are you going?
懦夫你说什么?
Coward, what were you saying?
嘿, 你竟敢打Aslam?
Hey you! How dare you hit Aslam?
对不起, 对不起我找了你们来拍电影
I'm sorry, I took you guys in my film.
上帝知道是什么让我来这..
God knows what made me come here...
我是那么蠢, 收拾东西到这个 人人找借口自相残杀的地方
I was so stupid to pack my bag and come to the place where people are just looking for excuses to kill each other
至少现在你们又少一个借口了
Well at least now you all have one less excuse
Sue, 对不起
Sue, we are sorry
你知道我们跟Pandey有过节, 所以剑拔弩张
You know we've got a problem with Pandey. There's a lot of bad blood.
我要是留下来, 肯定还会出事的
And if I stay, it's sure to happen again.
不不, 不会的
No, Sue.
我们会处理好的
We've worked it out.
不会给你惹麻烦的
You won't have any problems.
Sue, 我们都知道这部电影对你多重要
Sue... we all know how much this film means to you.
我们想帮你完成你来这的初衷
We want to help you finish what you came here to do.
大家都想你留下
Everyone wants you to stay.
我想你留下
I want you to stay.
说点什么..
Say something...
我害怕
I'm scared
别担心, 有可靠的人保护你
Don't worry, you're in safe hands.
来, 起来, 过来
Come on... Get up... Come here.
她哪也不去了
She's not going anywhere.
现在放松下
Now just chill.
接下来的四周是我一生最困难的
The next four weeks were the hardest in my entire life
也是最快乐的
and the happiest
"采取一些黄泥, 从这片土地"
Take some soil of my land
"采取一些香气, 从阵阵风里"
the scent of this air...
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒个嗒个似鼓点"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart...
"还有鲜红血滴, 热情蕴藏在这里"
And the zeal, that races through my blood...
"把这些混在一起, 创造出新的颜色"
Take all these, and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour...
"并给我染上爱国的颜色, 朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour.
Bismil传出消息..
Bismil's sent a message...
勒克瑙的火车..
...that the Lucknow train...
装着帝国的钱财, 就在Kakori动手
...carrying the Empire's money... will be looted by us in Kakori...
边吃着Kakori的烤肉
...while eating Kakori kababs.
然后我们用钱买炸弹
And we will buy bombs with that money.
饶了它吧.. 要不然都不产奶了
Leave her alone... She will stop giving milk.
"染了我的梦想, 染了我的人民"
Give colour to your dreams. And those of your people.
"染了我的欢乐, 染了我的悲伤"
Give colour to your happiness. And your sadness too.
"染了许多世代, 染了这片土地"
Give colour to generations... Give colour to the field...
"染了我的心跳和它的韵律"
Give colour to the beat of your heart. And that of your music.
"染了镜子里我的倒影"
Give colour to every cheek. Give colour to your eyes...
"朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism my friend.
给我染上爱国的颜色
Watch as it brings out the colour...
"采取一些黄泥, 从这片土地"
Take some soil of my land
"采取一些香气, 从阵阵风里"
the scent of this air...
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒个嗒个似鼓点"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.
"还有鲜红血滴, 热情蕴藏在这里"
And the zeal, that races through my blood.
"把这些混在一起, 创造出新的颜色"
Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour.
"再给我染上爱国的颜色, 朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend. Watch as it brings out the colour.
嘿小子
Hey Short-stuff!
你收到Bismil的消息没?
Did you get Bismil's message?
没有? 那听着..
No. No! Then Listen...
八天后就动手抢Kakori的火车
The train that's Kakori... will be looted in eight days.
它装满了帝国的钱
It's loaded with the Empire's money.
你会抢吗?                           不会
Will you loot it? No.
我们要用它来买武器
We will be buying arms from it.
买什么?                           武器
What will we buy? Arms...
很好, 走吧
Yes... Very Good... go now.
"用一点爱, 煽焙平稳的火焰"
On a slow fire, won't you, put this passion to cook.
"让它前行, 遇到了河流"
Then as it simmers, add a babbling brook.
"并到了海洋, 再装进水罐"
Add a river, and an ocean. Maybe a pot of water.
"慢慢地撒, 轻轻地摇"
Then sprinkle a bit. Stir it all up.
"直到新的颜色诞生"
And watch as it brings out the colour.
"给我染上爱国的颜色, 朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
Bismil传出消息..
Bismil has sent a message...
勒克瑙的火车
...the Lucknow train...
装着帝国的钱财
...which carries the Empire's money...
我们七天后在Kakori动手
...will be looted by us in seven days, in Kakori...
拿这些钱去买炸弹
And we will buy bombs with that money.
"涂了周围村落, 涂了它的欢笑"
Now paint the whole town with it. Paint your very being.
"高高兴兴地涂, 全心全意地涂"
Paint your every vein with it. Paint it with a smile.
"涂了那些童年, 涂了青春年华"
Paint those childhood years, won't you. Paint the flush of youth.
"不要迟疑, 认真涂上色彩"
Don't hesitate, my friend.
"换上颜色, 涂上所有一切"
Paint your patriotism over everything.
"给我染上爱国的颜色, 朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"采取一些黄泥, 从这片土地"
Take some soil of my land, the scent of this air.
Take some soil of my land
"采取一些香气, 从阵阵风里"
the scent of this air.
"加上一些呼吸, 嗒个嗒个似鼓点"
Add the breath of my being, the throbbing of my heart.
"还有鲜红血滴, 热情蕴藏在这里"
And the zeal, that races through my blood.
"把这些混在一起, 创造出新的颜色"
Take all these and stir it. Then watch as it brings out the colour.
"给我染上爱国的颜色, 朋友, 给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
"给我染上爱国的颜色"
Watch as it brings out the colour.
""给我染上爱国的颜色.. 朋友"
Watch as it brings out the colour of patriotism, my friend.
1925年的Kakori抢劫
The Kokori robbery of 1925
都是从那时开始的
That where it all started
从那以后一切都会改变
Nothing would ever be the same after that
英国官兵, 有20到25人
British Officers... around 20 to 25 of them.
计划必须取消, Kakori就快到了, 快阻止Ashfaq
We have to call it off! We've nearly reached Kakori. Stop Ashfaq, quick.
Ashfaq, 停下
Ashfaq, stop!
现在退出太迟了
It's too late to back out now... Come on... Move!
进去!
Get inside!
看好所有窗户..
Keep the windows shut...
钥匙!
The keys!
你是逃不掉的
You won't get away with this.
给我钥匙!                        我没有钥匙
Give me the keys! - I don't have it.
Banwari, 准备锤子
Banwari get the sledge hammer.
我来对付他们, 你去拿钱
I'll handle them. You go get the money...
Kakori事件引起了对这群人的注意
Kakori send shockwave to obvious establishment
人们找到了新的英雄
People have found new heroes
而我们只能责怪自己
But we had no one to blame but ourselves
我们听到的
What we were hearing
是自己枪声的回响
were the echoes of our own guns booming
我已把自己献给了祖国的自由
I've committed my life to the freedom of this country.
安逸, 其它世俗的追求打动不了我
Comfort, and other worldly desires do not attract me.
我知道你希望我成家, 安定下来..
I know you want me to get married and settle down...
像天下父母一样
...like all parents do.
但自由是我的新娘
But freedom is my bride.
请求你们原谅, 你们顺从的儿子, Bhagat
I hope you'll forgive me. Your most obedient son, Bhagat.
我们休息一阵
Let's take a break.
早餐? 不要..?
Breakfast? No...
放在这
Put it there.
Dyer将军? 谁做得出这种事?
General Dyer? How can one even think of doing something like this?
不敢相信他在Jallianwala Baugh杀害了400人
I can't believe that he actually killed more than 400 people at Jallianwala Baugh.
379, 这个是官方数字
379... that was the official figure.
其实近1000人被杀害
Actually nearly 1000 people were butchered...
去年在Peer Sai陵, 我为Daljeet平安求的
Last year at the tomb of Peer Sai, I prayed for Daljeet's well being.
谁是Daljeet?
Who's Daljeet?
我们以前就是容忍的典型
We were the epitome of tolerance.
连蚂蚁也会反抗. 可我们习惯对什么都不反抗
Even an ant reacts. But we are conditioned to take everything lying down.
胡说! 是现今一代人缺乏行动的意愿
Rubbish! It's today's generation which lacks the will to do anything
Shaheed Uddham Singh听过吗?
Have you ever heard of Shaheed Uddham Singh?
他一路跑去伦敦杀死了Dyer
He went all the way to London and killed that Dyer.
因为他也经历了Jallianwala Baugh大屠杀
...because he was also a part of the Jallianwala Baugh massacre.
吃吧Sonia, 黄油会让你骨头强硬
Eat it Sonia. The butter will strengthen your bones.
在旁遮普每个母亲至少要送一个儿子去军队
In Punjab every mother sends at least one son to the army.
我们为什么要退缩? 我们血液里流淌着牺牲
Why should we retreat? Sacrifice runs in our blood.
只有像DJ这样的笨蛋才退缩
Only idiots like DJ retreat.
怎么老是说回我?
Why does it always come back to me?
闭嘴吃你的煎饼
Shut up and eat your paratha.
这个国家用的最多的词是什么? "调整"
What is the most used word in this country? ADJUST!
四个人的座位坐六个人.. 有人会挤进来说:请调整
Six people sitting on a seat forfour... someone will squeeze in and say - 'Please adjust! '.
你干吗要调整, 伙计?
Hey! Why are you adjusting?
奇怪不是吗?
Strange. Isn't it?
在自己的国家, 却像动物似的被追捕
We are being hunted like animals in our own country...
Ashfaq, 你应该逃到阿富汗去
...Ashfaq you should cross the border and get to Afghanistan...
我们在那有很多穆斯林朋友, 你在那很安全
...We have many Muslim friends there. You will be safe with them.
何况, 你也是他们一员
After all, you're one of their own.
他们一员?
One of their own? Hmm...
你怎么不把我当自己人?
Why don't you think of me as one of your own?
Ashfaq, 我不是这个..
Ashfaq... I never meant...
我没想到会伤害你
I didn't mean to hurt you.
这是我的, 也是你的国家
This is your country as much as it is mine.
你也有权利为她战斗和死亡
You have a right to fight and die for it too...
原谅我
...Forgive me.
Ram, 我们不要说死..
Ram, let us not talk of dying...
我祈祷, 我们都能看到孙儿生活在印度自由的土地上
I pray, that we all live to see our grandchildren grow up in a free country.
Ram, 跑!
Ram run!
你的同伙在哪?
Where are your other friends?
Azad在哪?
Where's Azad?
Azad不是轻易能找得到的
Azad was not a man to be found easily
一个伪装的高手
A master of disguises
他们来去自由
They appeared and vanished at will
几个月的徒劳后
After months of frustration
不列颠政府找到了突破点
The breakthrough came for the British goverment
Banwari, 囚禁下最弱的革命者
Banwari, weakest revolutionary in captivity
给了我们Bismil和Ashfaqullah下落的人
A man who had given us to whereabouts for Bismil and Ashfaqullah
同意作饵引Azad上勾
agreed to be the bait to trap Azad
我们找到了我们的犹大
We had found our Judas
Banwari
Banwari!
歌舞真让人叫绝
I loved those songs and dances
你们电影里有吗? 这是我们种树的原因..
Do they happen in your films? That's the reason we grow trees in this country...
围着它们跳舞
to dance around them.
我们去哪?
So where are we going?
特别的一天, 特别的地点
Special day, special place!
特别的一天?
Special DAY?
让人惊叹
It's amazing
我还是小孩子的时候, 就经常来这
Ever since I was a kid I used to come here...
看飞机起飞, 直到消失在天际
...to watch planes take off... and watch them till they don't disappear in the sky.
他们是在干吗?
What the hell are they doing?
真是难以相信
I don't believe them.
男孩子!
Men!
得了, 接受吧, 你也很想那么做
Come on, face it, you'd love to do that really.
什么? 脱掉衣服朝天空大叫?
What? Take my shirt off and howl at planes.
你要是这样我不介意
I won't mind if you do.
你就做梦吧
Dream on buddy...
男孩, 女孩, 还有女孩的跟屁虫Sukhi..
Boys and girls and Sukhi...
怎么老是我?
Why me all the time?
我有一个特别的声明
I want to make a special announcement...
我在想你愿不愿意跟我共度余生
I was wondering if you'd like to spend the rest of your life with me...
要是你没什么重要事情的话?
...that's in case you aren't doing anything important...
你能嫁给我吗?
Will you please marry me?
"不要言语, 带我同行"
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"哪有你的微笑, 就是我的终点"
I'll find happiness by your side I can't stay apart
"这幸福, 终于领悟"
My life tastes sweet now,
"从此这生活, 变得甜如蜜"
since you walked through that door.
"你怀抱的海岸, 我的船终停靠"
When your arms wrap around me, I know I've found my shore.
"不要言语, 带我同行"
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"入我心途, 好似那朦胧雨"
Sweep through the streets of my mind like a gentle spring.
"梦想的旅行, 有了你的身影"
Walk through the corridors of my heart, fill the caravan of my dreams.
"你哼的曲调, 成了我的旋律"
I sway to the song of your soul.
"不要言语, 带我同行"
Without saying a word, you steal my heart.
"哪有你的微笑, 就是我的终点"
I'll find happiness by your side, I can't stay apart.
这人第一次给我印象的
The first thing that hit me about this man
是他的声音
was his voice
然后我清楚
I knew then
这不会是件轻松活
My job was not going to be easy
我过会再来
I'll come back later.
我的祈祷不会停止
My prayers won't stop
直到我的祖国获得自由
till my country gets its freedom.
我看你不能等到那个时候
I don't think you can wait till then.
我名字是James McKinley, 我来这找出..
My name is James McKinley. I'm here to find out from you...
Azad和其它恐怖分子躲在哪里
...where Azad and the other terrorists are hiding.
不是恐怖分子, 是革命者
Not terrorists. Revolutionaries.
拷问一个人
Breaking a man
一点一点
Bit by bit
他们说会随时间而习惯
They said it will get easy with time
却从来没有
It never did
酷刑持续了一段时间
The torture went on for some time
Bismil没有开口
But Bismil didn't break
两个人都忍受痛苦
Both men have pain their friend
他们没有招认
They didn't break
反而
Instead
他们做了我从没见过别的囚犯做的事
They did something I've never seen any prisoner do before
这一天我们与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白的脸庞
On this day, we walk with death and laugh at its pale spectre.
死亡不能压垮你Ashfaq, 你活在人民的心中
Death cannot take you Ashfaq, when you live in people's hearts and minds.
我想是诗歌把他们连系在一起
I think it was the poetry, that held their soul together
当酷刑把他们的身体撕裂
As the torture tore their body apart
酷刑没有奏效
The torture didn't work
于是我们想的别的办法
So we thought of other ways
孩子, 这是圣可兰经
This is the Holy Quran.
像Bismil这样的印度教徒在创造他们自己的国家
Hindus like Bismil will create a country for themselves.
穆斯林没好处而是被利用
What will a Muslim like you get out of it? They're just using you.
他不是为印度教而战, 是为印度自由而战
He's not fighting for Hindu freedom, he's fighting for Hindustan's freedom.
但是, 你是不会明白的
But you won't be able to understand this.
你做奴隶太久甚至都开始喜欢了
You've been a slave so long you've begun to like it.
说出Azad和其它恐怖分子的藏身处
Tell us where Azad and the other terrorists are...
你们还能保住性命
...You can still save yourself.
12月19号(全印非婆罗门结盟达成)
19 December.
这不是你的错, McKinley先生
It's not yourfault...
你只是在履行职责
...you're only doing your duty.
这怎么能真的发生?
How can this be real?
告诉我
Tell me
告诉我!
这怎么会是神的道路?
How can this be the way of God
请照顾这些会到你门口的人
Please look after the one, they'll arrive at your door
哦, 上帝
Oh my God
非常抱歉我还有虚荣..
I'm utterly sorry I've vanity
伙计们, 怎么样?
Hey guys, what's up?
有人死了吗?
Whats wrong? Did someone die?
Sue, 我从没见他们这么严肃
Sue... I haven't seen these guys so serious.
你对他们做了什么?
What are you doing to my friends?
没什么, 是他们.. 开始融入角色了
It's not me... it's them. They've really begun to get into this.
Laxman, 不一起去吗?
Hey Laxman, aren't you coming along?
不, 下次吧
No. Some othertime.
来吧, 是我在这的最后一晚了
Come on. It's my last night in town.
不, 我很饿
I'm not really hungry.
看我们吃, 走吧
Watch us eat then. Come on.
走吧..
Come on...
为Sonia和Ajay, 敬两人订婚, 祝激情浪漫到永远
To two lovebirds with the most insanely romantic engagement in the whole wide world...
我一生只为两样疯狂
I'm insane only about two things in my life.
一个是飞行, 一个是Sonia
Sonia and flying.
你很幸福, 能对什么充满热情
You're lucky to feel so passionately about something.
你有你的诗歌啊
You have your poetry Aslam.
就像DJ有他的歌唱
Just like DJ has his singing.
每人都有热情, 只需找到是什么
Everyone has passion for something inside them, they just have to find this 'thing'.
就像我们的革命者
Just like our revolutionaries...
他们对自由的热忱超过了自身
...their passion for freedom was greater than their love for their own lives.
这世界没什么值得付出生命, 没有
There's nothing in this world worth giving your life for. Nothing!
正确
Correct
重新来
Repeat.
悠着点, 喝很多了
Easy DJ...
好, "妈妈"
Yes mama.
有值得付出生命的东西
There are things worth giving your life for Karan.
说说看
Please.
Bhagat Singh, Azad, Bismil, Ashfaq.. Like what?
Look at Bhagat Singh and Azad and the rest of those guys.
他们为了国家献身
They gave their lives for this country.
结果呢? 白死了
Look what happened. All for nothing.
到现在也是个烂摊子, 又有谁在意?
It's a shit-hole today.
我在意
I give a shit.
像Ajay这样为国家奉献的人在意
People like Ajay who fight for their country give a shit.
所以你们才能睡得安稳
So that people like you can sleep peacefully.
Sonia, 别感情用事, 现实点
Sonia get real.
Sonia说得对
Sonia's right.
Sue, 你是外国人说说还行
Sue, it's all-fine for a foreigner like you to say all this...
可在这, 人民还在为生存根本奋斗
Out here we're fighting for basics.
食物, 衣服, 房屋
...food, clothing and shelter.
在这你要想改变什么, 只会变得更糟
Out here you try to change things you'll get even more screwed.
腐败简直就刻在我们的基因里
Corruption is in our DNA.
这个国家没有未来
There is no future for this country.
她在讲过去, 你却想未来
She's talking about the past, you're thinking about the future...
一只脚在过去, 一只脚在未来
One leg in the past and one leg in the future,
所以我们在现在"尿尿"
that's why we're pissing on the present...
DJ, 你闭嘴!
DJ, you just shut up
起码认真一次
For once in life get serious.
Karan, 置身事外评论很简单..
Karan, it's easy to sit on the outside and be a critic...
责怪他人更加简单
...blaming others is even easier.
你们怎么不出去改变这一切?
Why don't you go out there and change things?
勇敢站起来
Take a stand.
加入政界, 警局, 政府, 清理社会
Join politics, the police force, government and clean it up.
可你们不会! 我告诉你们为什么
But you won't! I'll tell you why...
因为那要付出相当的努力
Because that takes hard work
抱怨要容易得多
It's easier to crib.
什么也不会变的
Nothing's going to change.
你可以拼死尝试, 但不会有什么不同
You can go to your grave trying... it won't make any difference.
对.. 唯一的不同是怎么死
Correct... the only difference will be how you go to your grave...
DJ 悠着点
DJ relax
我没有醉, 我醉了吗, Sue?
I'm not drunk. Am I drunk Sue?
看, 导演说了算. Cut
See, the director's word is final. Cut it!
说到哪了?
Where were we?
死法
The end up style
死后怎样去坟场
On the way to our graves.
我们死了都会包在裹尸布里
We'll all be wrapped in white shrouds when we die.
只有Ajay包在国旗里
Only Ajay will be wrapped in the national flag.
DJ, 说够了
DJ stop it
Karan, 随你怎么说
Karan, you can say whateveryou want,
我们死了连街上的狗都不会叫
not even the street dogs will bark when we die.
但Ajay会有21声鸣枪致敬
But Ajay will get a 21 gun salute.
Karan, 给你的
Karan, this is for you.
给我的? 谢谢
For me? Thanks dude.
反正女孩子不管怎样都喜欢他
The girls fall for him anyway...
夹克要给人的话, 也该给我
If anyone deserves the jacket, it's me.
哇! 大婶, 多孝顺的媳妇
Wow! What a dutiful daughter-in-law.
来吧, 摸未婚夫的脚
Come on, touch your fiance's feet.
DJ说得对, 来吧
DJ's right. Touch my feet, madam.
看到了, 我国的妇女要忍受多少规矩
See what women in this country have to put up with?
我觉得DJ说得对, 你该遵守你的传统
I think DJ's right. You should respect your traditions.
看, 连Sue也同意..
See, even Sue agrees...
一个女人的地位就是他丈夫的脚
...a woman's place is at her husband's feet.
这两个真是孩子
These two can be such children.
他们一半时间吵架, 一半时间和解
They spend half their time fighting. The other half making up.
甜饼, 你就不能久待会?
Sweetie-pie, can't you stay a while longer?
不行, 我必须要走..
No, I have to go...
甜饼!
SWEETIE -PIE!
行了, 伙计们
Shut up guys.
闭嘴啊, 妈都听到了
Shut up yaar... Ma will hear everything.
我知道Sue现在的感受
I know how Sonia must be feeling right now...
我父亲以前也在军队
...my father was also in the army.
我也曾经这样想
I used to think that way too...
当时我跟Ajay他爸新婚
...when Ajay's father and I first got married.
然后想到做空军飞行员的妻子
But then you realize something about being an Air-force pilot's wife.
想到丈夫已经把生命交给了国家
You realize that your husband has pledged his life forthe country.
你能为他做的, 就是控制情绪不要脆弱
The least you can do for him, is control your emotions. Not be weak.
我很高兴, Ajay选了你这样的好女孩
I'm so happy Ajay's chosen a girl like you...
现在我可以安心死了
...now I can die in peace.
说什么呢, 妈
Don't talk nonsense Ma.
你还有很多时间, 跟很多孙子孙女呢
You'll have many more years... ...and a dozen grandchildren too.
孙子孙女? 要有足够时间来造人啊
Grandchildren? First you've got to stay home long enough to make them, dude.
号角鸣响, 敌人出动, 战斗已来临
The bugle sounds, the enemy wakes. The battle is upon us.
我们心里, 自豪坚定, 和英勇在膨胀
And in our hearts, we feel the swell, of pride and steel and valour.
乌云笼罩了大地, 我们誓死血战
For we will play the game of blood, if dark clouds shroud our land.
因为今日与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白脸庞
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
我们不惧怕残忍尖刀, 勇气更为锋利
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
面对威胁绝不屈服, 仰头向祖国母亲
We will not lower, in the face of threats, a head raised to its mother.
我们不惧怕残忍尖刀, 勇气更为锋利
We will not fear those cruel swords, our courage is far sharper.
面对威胁绝不屈服, 仰头向祖国母亲
We will not lower, in the face of threats, a head raised to its mother.
让他们知道怯懦行径, 只会火上浇油
For let them know, their cowardly deeds, just serve to stoke our fires.
因为今日与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白脸庞
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
我们今天互相道别, 了知是自身的终结
We bade farewell, to this day, knowing it could be our last.
我们发誓献出生命, 在战斗中绝不退缩
We swore to play, with our lives, never waver in our task.
因在这命运的筵席, 我们是最后的宾客
For we are but the last, few guests, served at fate's great banquet.
无法镇压狂怒的风暴, 是这革命的精神
We cannot quell, the raging storm, the spirit of revolution.
它流淌在我们的血液, 就像熔岩在滚动
For it now courses in our veins, like lava truly molten.
我们给他们两个教训, 便是恐惧和坚毅
We will teach them, the twin lessons, of fear and fortitude.
我们的目标埋藏不住, 勇敢是我们灯塔
Our goal cannot now hide for long, when courage is our beacon.
因为今日与死亡同行, 嘲笑它苍白脸庞
Because this day, we walk with death, and laugh at its pale spectre.
整个国家都在悼念Lalaji的战亡
The entire country is in deep mourning of the Lalaji's death
就在Lalaji死前, 他说
Just before his death, Lalaji had said
每次抗击都是英帝国主义棺材上的一颗钉
Every blow ended me, is a nail in the coffin of British imperialism
是暴风雨来临前的宁静
It was the calm before the storm
我们必须采取严厉的措施
We have to take drastic measures.
什么意思?
What drastic measures?
干掉他
Kill him.
走
Com'on.
Bhagat, 跑! 快!
Bhagat run! Quick!
你来啊, 如果想死的话
You! Get going.
接下来的第二天
On the day that followed
Azad, Bhagat Singh和其他人都不见了
Azad, Bhagat Singh and others went missing
正是这时他们创造了新词
This was the period when they coin the 2 words
Inquilab Zindabad (革命万岁)
Inquilab Zindabad
这个词成了印度自由运动的口号
Two words that became the slogan for the Indian freedom movement.
好主意!
Great idea!
但Bhagat, 这样没法逃脱
But Bhagat, escaping will be impossible.
我们主要的任务是被抓..
Our main mission is to get caught...
而不是逃脱
...not escape.
什么?
What?
如果被抓将会有审判
If we get caught there will be a trial...
我们有机会发言
...we'll get a chance to speak.
将会被听到
We'll be heard.
可如果被抓, 一定会被绞死
But if they catch us, they'll hang us for certain.
我知道
I know.
要开启聋子耳朵, 需要有力的呼喊
But it takes a loud noise to open deaf ears.
Inquilab Zindabad (革命万岁)!
LONG LIVE THE REVOLUTION!
他们用了烟雾弹
Smoke bombs
想让英格兰从美梦中苏醒
intended to awaken England from her dreams
而他们远不止达成了目标
And they had more than achieve their task
帝国主义灭亡!
DOWN WITH IMPERIALISM!
"感受这躁动.."
Feel the unrest
"余烬在燃烧"
The embers, they are burning.
"潮儿在涨动, 风儿在转向"
The tide, it's turning. You can feel the winds of change
"感受这躁动.."
Feel the unrest sweep through the land Feel the unrest
我们是政治犯
We are political prisoners...
应该可以给我们书本, 纸笔
...we should be allowed books... ...writing material...
还有至少一份新闻日报
...and at least one daily newspaper.
拿不到就禁食, 会继续抗议
We will not eat till then. The hunger strike will continue.
禁食和拷打持续了114天
The fast and torture went on for 114 days
114天!
114 days
史上任何革命任何人也没有持续过这么久
Never before in the history of any revolution that anyone last it so long
在这样的状态下
in such a human conditions
我们能摧毁他们的身体
We can crush these young boys
但摧不毁他们的灵魂
but we cannot crush their soul
"言语不会畏惧, 我们道出心声"
Our words won't falter now, We will speak our mind.
"梦想不会放弃, 我们不会退缩"
We won't back down now. Our dreams we won't leave behind.
"风暴不会消亡, 我们反抗不公"
We won't let the storm die. Injustice we will defy.
"感受它占据你, 感受你的灵魂"
You can feel it possess you now. Feel it, your soul, claim.
"将这精神饮下, 感受它流淌全身"
Drink this spirit in one long swallow. Feel it course through your veins
"让这狂欢开始, 感受身体摇摆"
Let the celebrations begin now. Feel your body sway.
"呼吸感受鲜活, 让这风暴持续"
In every breath feel more alive. To keep the storm at bay
"眼里看到这躁动, 扫过整个大地"
See the unrest in those eyes. See it all around.
"还有心也在躁动, 感受这躁动"
See it in the air, my friend. And in those hearts, abound.
"眼里看到这躁动, 扫过整个大地"
Feel the unrest sweep through the land
"还有心也在躁动, 感受这躁动"
See it in the air, my friend. And in those hearts, abound.
"风儿它已经转向, 潮水也在涨动"
The winds of change are blowing now The tide it is, a turning.
"为了真理而拼搏, 感受这躁动"
The moment of truth is upon us now It's time to do or die.
"我们被那阴影吞没, 出来时会更明亮"
We are engulfed in the shadows But we will come out brighter.
"感受这躁动.."
Feel the unrest. Feel the unrest.
漂亮吧?
Pretty huh?
我喜欢它们
I like these ones
可能会买下来
I think I'll buy them
真的很漂亮
Pretty nice huh? Very pretty.
现在报道最新新闻..
In breaking news today...
一架MIG-21战斗机失事坠毁
...a MIG-21 fighter plane has just crashed...
这是六个月来发生的第二起事故
...this is the second such crash in the past six months...
国防部长已下令调查此事件
The Defence Ministry has ordered an investigation into the crash.
我们刚刚收到消息, 飞行员..
We have just received news that the pilot...
..Ajay Rathod上校在事故中遇难
...Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod has died in the crash.
Rathod上校没有从飞机上跳伞..
Flight Lt Rathod apparently did not eject from the burning plane...
而是将它开离Ambala, 坠毁在一片空地
Instead he steered it away from Ambala city and crashed it in an open field.
以此挽救生命
Thus saving many lives
观众也许还记得..
Viewers may recall...
到目前为止, 印度空军已有163架MIG-21失事..
...that until now, 163 MiG-21 of IAF have crashed...
66名飞行员丧生
...and 66 pilots have lost their lives.
"这'捉迷藏'玩得太久, 现在回家来吧"
This game of hide and seek has gone on too long, come home now, won't you.
"我能去哪, 将你找寻"
I've searched high and low,
"你的母亲已疲倦"
these old eyes are weary so, come home now won't you.
"天色已晚, 我多么担心"
Dusk is spreading like the ache in my heart,
"泪眼矇眬, 快回家来吧"
my vision blurs, come home now won't you.
"如何解释我的所在, 妈"
I'm in a place you wouldn't believe Ma.
"无尽的天空任我翱翔"
Endless skies I can soar.
"就像童话故事, 有着美丽, 纯洁和梦幻"
Just like your fairy tales, it's filled with dreams.
"我的风筝就在这里, 无忧无虑飞翔"
A sea of hope with no shore.
"希望没人将线剪断, 也不会被偷走"
My soul flies here, like a kite without fear. No one to cut my strings, no more.
Ajay Rathod上校始终坚持到最后
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod stayed in the plane until the very end...
驾驶飞机飞离Ambala城
...and steered the plane clear of Ambala city.
从而挽救了许多生命
Thereby saving many lives.
然而Ajay Rathod上校却牺牲了自己
Unfortunately, the captain Ajay Rathod lost lives
过去12年印度空军有100多架MIG-21飞机坠毁
In the last 10 years over 100 MIG-21 aircrafts of the IAF have crashed...
造成30多名飞行员丧生
...in which over 30 pilots have lost their lives.
国防部长请告诉我们, CAG(审计总署)报告称 政府使用的是俄国破旧的零部件
Defence Minister, CAG report says old & defective Russian spare parts were procured by the govt.
这是否说明高层的腐败?
Isn't this a case of high-level corruption?
不, 当然不是. 我亲自向议会澄清过
Not at all. I've personally clarified the issue in parliament.
这完全是污蔑
This is a downright lie.
现在的年轻人飞行时轻率而不负责
The youngsters of today are brash and irresponsible when it comes to flying planes.
不! 我不同意..
No! I don't agree...
Ajay Rathod是个飞行能手..
Flt. Lt. Ajay Rathod was an ace pilot...
是我调教的
...who I trained...
他获得过金牌奖章, 是最年轻的夜间飞行员
He was a gold medallist. The youngest to clear night sorties.
飞行超过1000小时
With over 1000 flying hours...
没有哪个不负责的飞行员能做到这点
This can't be the record of an irresponsible pilot.
国防部长, 这体系的腐败还会持续多久..
Defence Minister, how many more pilots will you send to their graves...
你还会葬送多少飞行员的性命..?
...before you stop the rot in the system?
"怎样才能让你看到这般景象"
If only I could show you this place, Ma.
"我在这里所喝的水, 来自瀑布"
Here waterfalls are made of rainbows.
"我跳跃所触及到的, 都是梦想"
There are no roses just bouquets of dreams Ma. Their scent, no flower can hope for.
"想找阴凉却发觉并不炎热"
Here sunlight and shadow walk hand in hand.
"一切都是那样地清新"
Everything seems bright and new.
"在这什么都有, 妈可是"
But what is heaven, and all its wonders,
"没有你, 我觉得孤单"
when Ma, I don't have you.
从现在起, 政府会敕令..
From now on, the government will make sure that...
只有经验丰富的飞行员能驾驶这些飞机
...only experienced pilots are given access to these machines...
而不是像Ajay Rathod这样鲁莽的飞行员
...and not to rash pilots like Ajay Rathod.
他妈的在说些什么!
What the hell is he talking about!
我欢迎任何调查, 我没什么好隐藏
I welcome any investigation. I have nothing to hide.
这该死的MiG调查不该影响我们
This damn MIG investigation shouldn't take us down.
放心先生, 公众的记忆短暂, 何况还有我们呢
Relax Sir. Public memory is short. Besides, we'll handle things.
死去的飞行员, 媒体上会持续很久
Dead pilots, live very long in the news.
然后人们就加入空军去"牺牲", 不是吗?
But then, they join the forces to sacrifice their lives. Don't they?
此刻形势非常紧张
The situation is tense at the moment.
愤怒和不满在增长
There is growing anger and discontent.
直接针对政府, 尤其是国防部长
Directed largely towards the government. Especially the Defence Minister.
Ajay Rathod的母亲就在这里
We have with us Ajay Rathod's mother...
政府难逃其咎
The government can't wash its hands off the issue like this.
他们应给公众交待
They are answerable to the public.
如果MiG的零件有质量隐患, 为什么还要去买?
If the MIG spare parts were of doubtful quality, why were they bought in the first place?
为了什么?
For what?
为了钱吗?
Money?
但钱不能让我儿子起死回生
Money won't bring our children back.
国防部长在道义上应受谴责
The Defence Minister is morally responsible.
他应该引退
He has to resign.
看来国防部腐败的面纱已被揭开
It looks like the veil has been pulled off the defence scam.
但是能暴露多少?
But how much will be revealed?
Mishra, 是怎么回事?
Mishra, what's happening?
Ajay Rathod不是个新手..
Ajay Rathod was not a novice...
他没有让飞机坠落在城镇
...he didn't let his plane crash into the town.
出现状况时他没有逃命
When it developed a snag he didn't try to save his life.
他驾离了Ambala, 救了上千的人民
He steered it clear of Ambala ...saving thousands of civilians.
而国防部长却称他"轻率"
Yet the Defence Minister calls him rash.
我不会走.. 这是为了Ajay
I'm not moving... this is for Ajay.
有可能变得不可收拾, 大婶
This could turn ugly, Aunty.
让他们来吧
Let it.
"为了改变这现状"
Our blood is ranging. It's flowing through the streets.
"血液在流淌"
But it won't go in vain
"映在我眼睛里, 那血液在流淌"
Our eyes are blood shot for a purpose. A cause we will attain.
"从这身躯滴落, 附着这大地"
It fell from our bodies, embraced the earth.
"从大街小巷往外扩散, 流过.."
Went winding through streets. A river of courage ...it surged and swept.
"为了创造新色彩, 血液在流淌"
It flowed to make a new beginning
"随着这敞开的伤口, 伴着这抽搐的疼痛"
From gaping wounds, and gashes large,
"缓慢地, 缓慢地"
it oozed, slowly and steadily.
"置疑的手指, 回应是拳头"
While the pointing fingers, got fists in reply,
"与此同时"
yet, our blood was raging.
"血液在流淌"
It flowed not in vain but with a reason.
"为了改变这现状, 血液在流淌"
A cause we will attain.
"映在我眼睛里, 血液在流淌"
Our eyes are blood shot for a reason. A cause we will attain.
"从这身躯滴落, 附着这大地"
Our blood is raging. It's flowing through the streets.
"从大街小巷往外扩散, 流过.."
Went winding through streets. A river of courage ...it surged and swept.
"为了创造新色彩, 血液在流淌"
It flowed to make a new beginning Yet, our blood was raging.
"血液在流淌"
Yet, our blood was raging.
快去叫医生, 这里交给我们
Someone get a doctor! Quick! We'll take it from here.
请在这耐心等候, 我们会处理
Please patient, we'll take care
他们在殴打群众..
They were beating up innocent people...
你为什么不阻止?
Why didn't you stop them?
你抗议政府, 我们自己的党
You protested against the government, our own party...
是不可接受的
That's unacceptable.
抗议不是针对政府..
The protest was not against the government...
而是为了真相
...it was for the truth.
死了这么多飞行员
So many pilots have died...
他们为国家战斗牺牲
...young innocent boys who were fighting for our country... killed...
而政府里有人拿这个来赚钱
...so that someone in the government could make money.
我们的党却无动于衷
And our party office doesn't do a thing about it.
来, 坐
Come... Sit down.
喝茶
Have some tea.
Laxman, 政治是没有感情的
Laxman, in politics there's no place for emotions.
我们对你有很高的期望
We have big plans for you.
很高期望
Big plans.
Mishraji, 扔块骨头, 只有哈巴狗才摇头晃尾
Only dogs salivate when you show them bone Mishraji.
大妈还好吗?
How's Aunty?
他们在做MRI扫描
They're doing an MRI.
她陷入了昏迷
She's slipped into a coma.
严重的脑损伤, 加上儿子死去的打击
Severe skull damage, coupled with the shock of her son's death.
有一道很深的伤口, 要特别注意
That's an ugly gash. You need attention.
Aslam, Aslam怎么样?
Aslam... How's he?
你们来干什么? 做得还不够?
What have you come for? Haven't you done enough damage?
伯伯, 不是你想的那样
Uncle, it isn't what you think.
我不感兴趣你想什么, 要说什么..
I'm not interested in what you think, In what you want to do...
我只说这一次
I'm just going to say this once.
Aslam不知道什么才对他好
Aslam doesn't know what's good for him.
他容易冲动, 做事随心不动脑
He's an emotional boy, always has been. He listens to his heart, not his head.
像我们这样的人不好过
These are bad times, for people like us.
不要连累了他
Don't take him down with you.
进来吧, 他在里面
He's inside. Go on...
各个部分还能运转吧?
All parts working?
别惹我笑, 傻瓜. 很痛
Don't make me laugh, idiot. It hurts
大妈怎么样?
How's Aunty?
在昏迷
She's in a coma.
这种事怎么会发生在我们身上?
How can this be happening to us?
吃点东西吗?
Some dinner?
不伯母, 不麻烦了
No, don't worry Aunty.
我们刚从医院出来, 就来看看Aslam
We just came to see Aslam. We've got to get back to the hospital.
保重
Take care.
听着, 我..
Listen... I...
我想跟你说
...I'm sorry.
对不起
sorry
吃吧
Please eat.
什么都一团糟
Everything's falling apart...
我只能站着看
...and all I can do is stand and watch.
我们这样的人不起作用
People like us don't count out here.
体系这么糟糕
This system is so messed up
死100多个"Ajay"也无济于事
a hundred more Ajay's can die
什么也不会变
and nothing will change.
Ajay什么都做得很对, 他的一生
Ajay did everything right, all his life...
他是个好飞行员, 好朋友, 好儿子
...he was a good pilot, a good friend, a good son...
从没伤害过任何生命
...he never harmed a soul.
他不该是这个下场
...he didn't deserve this...
Sonia也不该承受这痛苦
...Sonia didn't deserve this...
那晚当我看着DJ睡觉
As I watch DJ sleep that night
我冒出了个奇怪的想法
A funny thought caught me
也许DJ没有睡去
Maybe DJ wasn't sleeping
也许他们没人是
Maybe none of them were
也许他们都在觉醒
Maybe they were all waking up
Karan, 他们在糟蹋你的夹克
Hey Karan... they've spoilt your jacket.
印度万岁!
Long live India!
那个混蛋又逃脱了
The scoundrel got away with it again.
我们什么都做不了
There's nothing can we do...
当法律偏向这样的人..
...when the law of the land protects people like the Defence Minister.
我们就得采取严厉的行动
We have to take drastic measures.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
要怎么做?
Do what?
杀掉他
Kill him.
什么?
What?
杀掉国防部长
Kill the Defence Minister!
你们都疯了?
Are you crazy?
我们不是杀人犯, Sonia
We aren't killers Sonia.
但他们是
But they are.
你也疯了, Karan?
Have you lost it Karan!
这不是杀戮的欲望..
It's not a blood lust...
而是为了正义
...it's a matter of justice.
我去搞枪
I'll get the gun.
不要火上浇油Pandey, 我们不能为了点小事杀人
Don't fuel things, Pandey. We can't start killing people for any small reason.
你觉得Ajay的死是小事?
You think Ajay's death is a small reason?
Ajay的妈是小事?
Ajay's mother is a small reason?
你要理解一下, Karan
You've got to understand Karan.
必须要为Lala Lajpat Rai的死报仇
Lala Lajpat Rai's death has to be avenged.
Scott必须死
Scott has to be killed.
可是..
But...
我一直以为我们什么也不信
I always thought we didn't believe in anything.
我也是
So did I
直至今天
Until now.
我们都疯了?
Have we all gone crazy?
他每天早上8点要散步
He takes a morning walk at 8 a.m. Everyday
我们在那时动手
We'll kill him then.
到时动手! 谁来动手? 我们谁来动手?
Who's we, huh? Who's going to pull the trigger?
我
I'll do it!
虽然早上警卫松懈, 但还是有被抓的危险
Even though the morning security is relaxed there is still a danger of getting caught.
现在没机会回头了
There is no looking back now!
今天早上国防部长在散步时 两个身份不明的持枪人向他开枪
The Defence Minister was on his morning walk when two unidentified gunmen opened fire.
他胸口中了三枪, 在去医院途中死亡
He was hit by three bullets in his chest, and was declared dead as he reached the hospital.
没有组织声明对此负责
No group has yet claimed responsibility for this incident.
政府发言人认为这是试图影响政府稳定
Government spokespersons believe that this is an attempt to destablise the government.
因为某些胆小的恐怖行径, 国家失去了一位伟大领袖
The country has lost a great leader because of the cowardly act of some terrorists.
他是个真正的爱国将士
He was a true soldier, a true patriot.
他对国家的贡献无法用言语表达
His contribution to the country cannot be described in words.
Sukhi!
同时我们的线报捕获了一次电话通话
Meanwhile our sources have discovered a telephonic conversation...
证明了中间商Rajnath Singhania参与了军火交易
...involving middle man Rajnath Singhania in an arms deal.
通话就发生在国防部长被刺的几天前
This conversation took place just a few days before the Defence Minister's assassination.
'俄国人想降低我们的佣金'
The Russians want us to reduce our commission.
'你没跟他们说, 这不是国防部的交易, 而是我们的交易'
Didn't you tell them, its not a defence deal, but our deal.
'所以我跟他们说, 他们自己看着办'
That's why I told them. - "Take it or leave it"
我们走
Let's go.
Paaji, DJ在哪?
Paaji, where's DJ?
他们刚才还在这
They were just here.
他整晚都没回来
He hasn't come home all night.
没什么事吧?
Is everything alright?
他说要在DJ那过夜
He said he'd be spending the night at DJ's.
看见DJ吗?
Have you seen DJ?
没事吧?
Is everything alright?
我找不到他
I can't find him
我谁都找不到, Sonia, Aslam, 不知道他们在哪
I can't find anyone, Sonia, or Aslam I don't know where they are
过来..
Come with me...
坐
Sit
别担心.. 他们会没事的
Don't worry... nothing will happen to those boys...
Daljeet就是这么淘气
Daljeet has always been a brat...
他曾经开着摩托车, 消失好几天
...he used to disappear on his bike for days...
我害怕..
I'm scared...
不要怕
Don't be afraid...
老天会保佑他们的
God will take care of everything...
我们爱的人, 老天会照顾他们
God watches over the people we love.
国防部长, 烈士..
Defence Minister... the martyr...
印度最可爱的儿子..
...one of India's favourite sons... Scoundrel!
他们要给他国家荣誉勋章
They're honouring him with the National Medal of Honour.
我们的努力, 白费了
All our efforts, wasted.
人们需要知道真相
People need to know the truth.
是吗? 谁去说出真相?
...and who's going to tell them the truth?
我们! 我们要去自首
We have to surrender ourselves.
什么?
What?
警官, 抓我吧, 抓我吧, 我们要自首
Terriffic! You want us to walk right in and give ourselves up!
我们跟谁自首?
And who should we surrenderto?
警察, 不过是受制于人
The police are mere puppets.
那怎么办? 就这样坐着? 什么也不做?
Should we just sit back?
不! 把他们都杀了!
No! Let's kill them all!
是吗 Pandey?
Right Pandey?
谁让他闭嘴!
Someone make him shut up!
你早就知道你爸有份
You always knew that your father was in it.
你什么都知道
You knew everything.
我不知道, Sukhi..
No Sukhi...
你在说谎!
You're lying!
你一直想向你爸报仇
You always wanted to take revenge on your father.
Sukhi, 不要说了!
Sukhi, shut up!
我是谁, 凭什么说他?
Who am I to say anything?
DJ他是在利用你
DJ he's used you...
利用了我们所有人
...he's used all of us...
记住我说的话, 他爸会保他出去
Mark my words, his father will bail him out.
我们会被抓, 而我还不想死..
But we'll get caught. And I don't want to die DJ...
我不想死..
I don't want to die.
我们这么做都是为了Ajay
We did all this for Ajay.
现在怎么办DJ?
What will happen now DJ?
你想好了?
You've decided?
我得知道真相..
I need to know the truth...
别担心
don't worry.
我不担心, 只是别太晚
I'm not worried. Just don't be late.
你不会有事的Karan
Nothing will happen to you Karan.
我向你保证不会有事的
That's a promise.
只要把其它人的名字告诉我
Just give me the names of the others.
我会请最好的律师, 想尽一切办法
I'll get you the best lawyers, pull all the strings possible.
你是被逼的, 知道吗? 是被逼的
You were forced into it, do you understand? You were forced.
然后你就离开这个国家
And then you are out of this country
说话啊? 听到没有?
Do you get me?
说话啊, 妈的!
Say something, damn it
你父亲的名誉, 一生的事业都危在旦夕
Your father's reputation, his life's work is at stake.
你为什么这么做? 为什么?
Why did you do it?
你为什么这么做?
Why did you do it, Dad?
我? 我做什么了?
What did I do?
Ajay总是说, "我会为国家献身"
Ajay always said, "I'll give my life for this country."
"我不害怕死亡, 什么也不怕"
"...I'm not afraid of death."
而你想的, 却是逃亡出国
and all you can think of is sending me out of the country...
Ajay他被活活烧死
Ajay was burnt alive...
是你杀了他
You killed him!
你把他的生命当儿戏
You made a joke of his death...
我知道你很难受
I know you're very disturbed...
但你什么也不要想, 这事我来处理
Relax! Let me handle things.
我会想到办法的
I'll find a way out.
只有一个办法, 爸
Really Dad? Is there a way out?
当然
Of course.
你今晚就出国
You are going out of this country tonight
Sukhi, 你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this...
Sukhi, 结局可能很糟糕
Sukhi, this might end badly.
反正没有你们, 我也一样糟糕
Without you guys it will end for me anyway...
傻小子
Idiot.
妈, 我答应你, Ajay不会白死的
Ajay's death, won't go in vain, Ma. I promise you.
是什么让这些人毫无畏惧?
What is it about these boys that makes them have no fear?
我想有时一个人能走这么远
I think sometimes a person can be pushed so far
到达超越恐惧的地步
that will to place beyond the fear
在那里找到奇怪的安宁
A place where find strange peace
可以自由地做正确的事
where you'll free yourself to do the right thing
因为有时, 这也是最难做到的事
Because sometimes, that's the hardest thing to do
然后我祈祷
Then I prayed for it
祈求原谅
I prayed for forgiveness
欢迎回来, 这里是... 你最喜欢的电台, 我是Rahul..
This is Rahul, and you've tuned in to your favourite radio show...
Karan, 真叫人惊喜! 你们怎么来了?
Hey Karan! What're you doing here?
我们要你帮个忙
We need a favour.
当然
Sure!
我们需要上电台
I need you to put us on air.
上广播电台?
Put you on air?
是, 直播!
Yeah, now!
'是, 现在, 直播'那是不可能的, 我会丢工作的
That's impossible man... I'll lose my job.
而且其实他们不付我钱
...as it is, they don't pay me.
那么现在该付你了
It's payback time.
好吧好吧, 你怎么说都好DJ! 电台都是你的
Hey! Whateveryou say DJ! It's your station.
枪! 他有枪!
Gun... He's got a gun!
Karan你进去, 我来处理
Karan you go in. I'll handle it.
继续播音, 别耍花招, 知道吗?
Keep the show on. Don't mess with us.
来, 走吧
Come on... leave.
Paaji, 里面还有人吗?
Paaji is anyone inside?
Uncleji, 走, 别停下
Uncleji run. Don't stop.
枪.. 保安他有枪!
Gun... Security he's got a gun!
别自作聪明
Don't be a wise guy.
每个人都出去!
Everybody leave! Out! Move!
别慌张, 我们不会伤害任何人
Don't panic we won't harm anyone.
走走!
Move! Move! Move!
快点, 快!
Hurry up, quick!
现在是早上6点05分. 你现正收听的是"夜色仍淡"
The time is 6:05 a.m. And you're listening to "The night is still young".
今天我们请到了一个特殊嘉宾
Today I've got a surprise guest for you.
我的一个老朋友Karan Singhania, 有话与大家分享
An old friend of mine Karan Singhania, who just dropped in to say something to all of you...
我叫Karan Singhania, 我和我的朋友杀死了国防部长
My name is Karan Singhania... My friends and I... we killed the Defence Minister...
我再说一遍, 我和我的朋友杀死了国防部长
I repeat we killed the Defence Minister...
Ravi马上带我去广播站, 赶快!
Ravi take me to the radio station quickly. Hurry up!
我们不是恐怖分子, 背后也没有什么国外组织
We are not terrorists. We aren't backed by any foreign organisation.
我们不属于任何下政治组织
We don't even belong to any political group...
我们只是德里大学的5个学生
We're just five students from Delhi University.
我们杀害了国防部长..
We killed the Defense Minister because...
因为他害死了我们的朋友Ajay Rathod上校 和其它很多的空军飞行员
...he murdered ourfriend Flight Lieutenant Ajay Rathod and many other Air Force pilots...
我们杀了他因为他不仅害死了Ajay 还诋毁了他的名誉
We killed him because after he murdered Ajay, he murdered his name...
Ajay的母亲现在还在死亡线上挣扎
Ajay's mother, right now, is fighting for her life...
国防部长应该保卫国家, 而不是出卖国家
A Defence Minister is supposed to safegaurd a nation. Not sell it.
像他那样的人不仅凌驾法律之上, 而且一手操控
Men like the Defence Minister aren't just above the law... they control it.
我们杀了他因为必须有人站出来抗议
We killed him because someone had to say, "Enough!".
我们也许错了
We might be wrong...
因为杀人是罪过
...because its a sin to kill someone.
但我们再也忍受不了了
But we couldn't tolerate it anymore.
今天我们在此坦白我们的罪过
Today we are here to confess to our sin.
今天我们在此告诉每个人, 应该行动了
Today we are here to tell everybody that something has to be done
必须行动了
It's got to be done.
我们刚得到消息国防部长的行刺者躲在"All India"广播大楼
We've just received news that Defence Minister's assassins are hiding in All India Radio building.
Karan Singhania与他的朋友仍然在线 听众可以拨打3291777
Karan Singhania and his friends are still with us. Listeners can call in on 3291777.
先来段音乐
Until then, here is "Roobaroo"
说完了
It's done.
"嘿伙计"
Hey, dude!
"现在明白了"
I just realized.
"有一团火, 在胸中燃烧"
There's a fire burning within me.
"新的黎明"
It's a new dawn,
"感受到光线"
I can feel its light
"这么明亮, 能把太阳烘烤"
Burn so bright, I could, scorch the sun
"我与这光, 面对面"
'Cause I'm face to face with the light
"这些梦想, 曾经失去"
The dream I once lost, I've found.
"重新找回, 它在盛放"
It's blooming,
"犹如钢铁, 已经融化"
it's melting,
"再次锻造, 得到升华"
notes re-arranging,
"它变成了, 星星的模样"
into a whole new melody.
监狱有好吃的吗?
Will they give us good food in jail?
好吃的? 接下来就想要啤酒了
Food? Next he'll want beer.
你们出名了, 全国各地的电话都打来了
You guys have become famous. Calls are pouring in from all overthe country.
来啊, 他们想跟你说话
Come on! They want to talk to you...
警察!
Police!
这不是真的. 他们从哪来的?
This is unreal man. Where did they come from?
我的事业要毁了
This will ruin my career...
闭嘴
Shut up!
Karan你去播音.. 我们没多少时间了
Karan you get on air... We don't have much time...
保重
Take care.
德里警方到达现场, 正对大楼被困的人进行救援
The Delhi police have reached the spot and are rescuing civilians trapped in the building.
..从孟买教堂门地区报道..
...reporting from Mumbai's Churchgate area...
..从古瓦哈蒂的科顿大学报道..
...reporting from Cotton College, Guwahati.
..从斯利那加的S.P.大学报道..
...reporting from S. P. College, Srinagar...
..从勒克瑙大学报道..
...reporting from Lucknow University...
我叫Prakash, 我想向你道贺
Hi, my name is Prakash. And I want to congratulate you.
你们杀了他做得对, 所有部长都该排起队来受死
You did the right thing by killing him. All our ministers should be lined up and shot.
Prakash, 你会杀掉哪一些部长?
Prakash, who all will you shoot?
这些腐败的部长是根据社会反映而选择的
These corrupt ministers are a reflection of our society. We've chosen them.
我们要改变自己从而带来改变
We need to change ourselves to bring about a change.
我是Indore的Sharma校长..
Hello! This is Principal Sharma from Indore...
你们当自己是法律树立了很坏的榜样
You have set a terrible example by taking the law into your own hands.
说得对, 我们很抱歉
You're right sir. We're sorry.
但是你说说有哪个政治家因为罪行入了监狱
But give me the name of one politician who has gone to jail for his crimes.
你的暗杀名单上还有谁?
Who else is on your hit-list? I
我们没有暗杀名单
We have no hit-list.
杀掉了国防部长你有什么感觉?
How do you feel after killing the Defence Minister?
我们杀了他不是出于杀戮欲
We did not kill him out of any blood lust...
如果被抓你们会被绞死, 你们不怕?
If you get caught you'll be hanged. Aren't you afraid?
不怕
No.
声称对此负责的大学生
The college students who have claimed responsibility...
还在里面
...are still inside.
Karan, 当我们为你们的勇气鼓掌时, 你们想过逃跑没?
Karan, while we applaud your courage, do you think you'll escape?
要是想逃就不来这了
If we wanted to escape, we wouldn't have been here in the first place.
一个也不要放过
Do not spare anyone.
我不想有任何幸存者
I don't want any survivor
我的老天, 他们在向我们开枪, DJ! ..
Shit! They're shooting at us DJ! They're shooting at us!
冷静一下!
Shut up for a second!
他们误以为我们是恐怖分子, 以为我们有武器
They're mistaking us for terrorists. They think we're armed.
等一会, 我来处理
Wait a minute! I'll try to handle it.
看看你都做了什么
No Sukhi! What did you do!
傻DJ, 我刚要和女孩子好上..
Shit DJ! Just when I was getting good with the girls...
我叫Indra, 你们和恐怖分子有什么区别呢?
My name is Indra. What's the difference between you and a terrorist?
有很大区别, 恐怖分子杀害无辜的人, 我们没有..
There's a big difference. Terrorists kill innocent people. We didn't...
快关上门
Aslam, close the door. Quick!
我们不是恐怖分子, 他们怎么..
We are not terrorists. Why don't they...
这不是杀戮欲, 而是为了正义
It's not a lust for blood... it's a matter of justice!
已经很清楚是群大学生, 为什么还要使用子弹?
Why are bullets being used when its clear that these are college students?
不管你们怎么做, 国家都不会变化 这里是印度, 它没有未来
No matter what you do, this country will never change. It has no future.
没有国家是完美的, 只能让它变得更好
No country is perfect. You've got to make it perfect.
加入警局, 军队, IAS(印度科学院)
Join the police, military, IAS...
成为政治体系的一分子
Become a part of the political system...
国家会变的, 我们会改变她的
This country will change... We will change it!
如果你们相信国防部长应该受到惩罚..
If you believed the Defence Minister deserved to be punished then...
那你的父亲呢? 怎么说一套做一套?
...what about the allegations against your father? Why such double standards?
我们会想出办法来的
We'll find a way to fix this.
只有一个办法, 爸
There's just one way to fix this Dad.
对不起, 爸爸
I'm sorry Dad...
我叫Daljeet Singh.
My name is Daljeet Singh.
生命有两种活法
There are only two ways to live your life.
忍受现有的方式
Tolerate things the way they are...
或者, 负起责任来改变
...Ortake responsibility to change them.
Karan Singhania来这之前已经杀了自己的父亲
Karan Singhania killed his father before coming here.
你流了很多血!
Shit DJ! You're bleeding badly!
放松, 它在我血管里待腻了, 它也想要自由
Relax! It got tired of flowing in my veins. It just wanted to be free.
Aslam.. Laxman.. Sukhi?
Aslam... Laxman... Sukhi?
都死了
All gone.
Karan, 我想我恋爱了
...Karan, I think I'm in love...
我从没告诉过你们
...I nevertold you dude...
我止不住对她的思念
...I can't stop thinking about her...
我知道, 她与众不同
I know... she's something else.
你们两个会成为很配的一对
You two'll make a great couple.
只有一个问题
There's just one problem though.
我不知道孩子会是黑还是白
I don't know Whether the kids will be black or white.
放开我! 他们不过是少年!
Let me go! They're just boys, damn it!
我一直认为世界上有两种人
I always believe there were two kinds of men in this world
面对死亡哭喊的人
One who go to that death screaming
面对死亡安静的人
And men who go to that death in silence
然后我遇到了第三种
And then I met the third kind
派出突击队是民主制度的死亡
Sending commandos is the death of democracy
今天是印度政治历史上悲伤的一天
Today is a sad day in the history of Indian politics
我们会把这火花演变成熊熊火焰
We'll turn this spark into a raging fire.
这会像汹涌的波涛终结这腐败
This will swell like a wave and will bring an end to corruption.
真相必须得到揭露, 如果 非要以这样的方式, 那我们都会赞同
The truth has to come out some way and if it has to come out this way then we are all for it
要想撼醒全国的人民, 我们就需要这样的"炸弹"
If we want to shake the entire population out of their slumber then we need an explosion like this.
我们不能总坐着讨论这些, 必须付诸行动
We are going to sit and just talk about the thing So we got to do some steps
而他们做到了, 他们做了正确的举动
And they have done it, they have taken a right step..
等我们从这里成长起来, 国家会变得美好没有腐败
When we grow out of this, well be a nation which is beautiful and free of corruption.
深深打动了我们的心, 不会很快忘记 我们会让梦想成为现实
in minds and hearts, that's not gonna fix up very soon And we'll see that
我们会行动起来
We will do it
神啊, 请接受这些孩子的牺牲
Lord, accept the sacrifices of these children.
我经常与Sonia来这
I come here with Sonia a lot
就像以前一样
Just like old times
有时我听见傍晚的微风带来声音
And sometimes I hear voices carried by the evening breeze
不是说话声, 只是声音
Not words, just sounds
欢笑声
Sounds of laughter
过来, Bhagat..
Come Bhagat...
爸爸, 你在干什么?
Dad, what are you doing?
我在播芒果种, 撒下一颗, 长出成片
I'm sowing mango seeds. If I plant one, a thousand will grow.
印度从1964年即开始使用MiG战斗机 在战役中起了相当作用
MiG fighter planes have served our country since 1964 and have been instrumental in winning us wars
然而15年来, 有206架MiG飞机坠毁, 78名飞行员丧生
However over the 15 years, 206 MiG planes have crashed and 78 pilots have lost their lives
为纪念这些空中勇士, 纪念他们为祖国献出了生命
In their memory and in honour of our Air Borne Warriors who have laid down their lives for our country
更多精彩请关注 极地影视 www.jddy.net